Guide to the Barbara Guest Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1940-2006; Series I
  - General correspondence
    - Rosenbach Museum & Library, 1985 November 7–1986 January 21 (Box 32, Folder 697)
    - Rosenthal, Sarah, 2003 October 22–2004 October 28 (Box 32, Folder 698)
    - Rosenwasser, Rena, 1983 August 11–2006 March 10 (Box 32, Folder 699-701)
    - Rounseville Rehab Center, 2006 February 28 (Box 32, Folder 702)
    - Rowe, Marsha, 1996 April 17 (Box 32, Folder 703)
    - Royal Academy of the Arts, 1991 October 24 (Box 32, Folder 704)
    - Royal Festival Hall, 1997 March 13–1997 April 18 (Box 32, Folder 705)
    - Roy, Camille, 1998 August 11–1999 March 14 (Box 32, Folder 706)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1979 July 5 (Box 32, Folder 707)
    - Russell, Frances M., 1961 October 4 (Box 32, Folder 708)
    - Russell, John, 1984 February 27 (Box 32, Folder 709)
    - "R" General (Box 32, Folder 710)
    - Sachs, Grace, 1958 November 20 (Box 33, Folder 711)
    - Saint James Press, 1969 March 5–1979 January 23 (Box 33, Folder 712)
    - Saint Mary's College, 2002 April 12 (Box 33, Folder 713)
    - Salander O'Reilly Galleries, 1998 July 14–2004 July 14 (Box 33, Folder 714)
    - Salembier, Anita, 2006 March 7 (Box 33, Folder 715)
    - Samuel, Alison, 1987 November 10 (Box 33, Folder 716)
    - Sandbach, John, 2004 May 19–2004 July 28 (Box 33, Folder 717)
    - Satterthwaite, Alfred, 1979 July 31–1985 April 17 (Box 33, Folder 718)
    - Scalapino, Leslie, 1994 February 16–1995 February 21 (Box 33, Folder 719)
    - SCARLET, 1990 October 4 (Box 33, Folder 720)
    - Schaffner, Perdita, 1968 July 30-1998 February 19 (Box 33, Folder 721)
    - Schaffner, Tim, 2001 July 30–2006 February 21 (Box 33, Folder 722)
    - Schaffner, Val, 2001 December 30–2006 March 9 (Box 33, Folder 723)
    - Schmidt, Michael, 1991–1999 (Box 33, Folder 724)
    - Schuman, Lellani, 1997 November 15 (Box 33, Folder 725)
    - Schuyler, James, 1954-1989-11-14 (Box 34, Folder 726)
    - Schwartz, Delmore, 1951 June 5–1951 June 13 (Box 34, Folder 727)
    - Schwartz, Leonard, 2002 September 17–2006 February 21 (Box 34, Folder 728)
    - Scribner, 2004 May 27 (Box 34, Folder 729)
    - Scott, Toni and Suki, 2002 December (Box 34, Folder 730)
    - Searls, Damion, 2004 June 6–2005 December 1 (Box 34, Folder 731)
      Includes photograph of two unidentified people
    - Seidenberg, Jocelyn, 2001 August 9 (Box 34, Folder 732)
      Includes notes about doctor appointments that seem unrelated but were enclosed with correspondence
    - Serafín, Jesulin, 2000 April 19 (Box 34, Folder 733)
    - Shearson Lehman Brothers, undated (Box 34, Folder 734)
    - Shelley Memorial Award, 2003 September 4–2004 April 26 (Box 34, Folder 735)
    - Shelon, Ivan, undated (Box 34, Folder 736)
    - Sherry, James T., 2003 February 8–2005 May 18 (Box 34, Folder 737)
    - Sherwin, Judith J., undated (Box 34, Folder 738)
    - Shimoda, Brandon, 2005 October 23–2005 November 24 (Box 34, Folder 739)
    - Shurin, Aaron, 2003 May 20–2003 October 15 (Box 34, Folder 740)
    - Sikelianos, Eleni, 1997 August 19–2001 December 21 (Box 34, Folder 741)
    - Silbert, Layle, 1976 December 24 (Box 34, Folder 742)
    - Silverleigh, Louis, 1985 November 14 (Box 34, Folder 743)
    - Simon's Rock of Bard College, 1988 November 21 (Box 34, Folder 744)
    - Sitwell, Reresby, 1986 February 3 (Box 35, Folder 745)
    - Six Towns Poetry Festival, 1996 January 23-October 9 (Box 35, Folder 746)
    - Skidmore College, 1993 April 29–1993 May 17 (Box 35, Folder 747)
    - Slacik, Anne, 2000 January 17–2002 March 22 (Box 35, Folder 748)
    - Slaff, Mosk & Rudman, 1990 June 8 (Box 35, Folder 749)
    - Slavin, Maeve, 2001 July 18–2005 January 10 (Box 35, Folder 750)
    - Slavin, Patrick, 2003 February 20–2005 March 9 (Box 35, Folder 751)
    - Slavitt, David R., 1984 August 22 (Box 35, Folder 752)
    - Slovak, Paul, 1999 November 19–2004 December 3 (Box 35, Folder 753)
    - Small Press Traffic, 1996 April 30–1999 September 3 (Box 35, Folder 754)
    - Smith, Dale, 1996 January 5 (Box 35, Folder 755)
    - Smith, Jane L., 1990 July 25 (Box 35, Folder 756)
    - Smith, Paul, 1977-11-01- (Box 35, Folder 757)
    - Smolin Gallery, undated (Box 35, Folder 758)
    - Smyers, Genny, 1980 April 21-2006 February 21 (Box 35, Folder 759-760)
    - Solebury School, 1985 November 8 (Box 35, Folder 761)
    - Something Else Press, undated (Box 35, Folder 762)
    - Southampton College, 1977 June 29 (Box 35, Folder 763)
    - South Bank Centre, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 764)
    - Southern Illinois University Press, 1964 May 14–1964 July 22 (Box 35, Folder 765)
    - Spahr, Juliana, 2004 November 18–2006 February 19 (Box 36, Folder 766)
    - Sparks, Esther, 1985 June 17 (Box 36, Folder 767)
    - Speirs, Robert, 2004 June 4–2004 June 16 (Box 36, Folder 768)
    - Stable Gallery, 1955 December 28–1962 May 20 (Box 36, Folder 769)
    - Stanford, Ann, 1977 May 4 (Box 36, Folder 770)
    - Stanford Humanities Center, 1997 March 19 (Box 36, Folder 771)
    - Stanoyevitch, Barry, 1996 January 21 (Box 36, Folder 772)
      Includes photograph
    - Stein, Abner, 1986 January 21–1986 March 10 (Box 36, Folder 773)
    - Stephenson, Shelby, 1989 February 2–1991 July 1 (Box 36, Folder 774)
    - Stevens, Jessica, 2002 March 14–2002 June 6 (Box 36, Folder 775)
      Includes page proofs for Barbara Guest's poem "First Prints"
    - Storer, Ottavia, 2003 September 25–2003 November 13 (Box 36, Folder 776)
    - Stowell, Phyllis, 1995 December 29–1997 April 18 (Box 36, Folder 777)
    - Stratis, Katie, 2002 May 23 (Box 36, Folder 778)
    - Strickland, Stephanie, 1996 June 19 (Box 36, Folder 779)
    - Stroffolino, Chris, 2002 March 12–2002 March 31 (Box 36, Folder 780)
    - Stuart, Gaby, 1979 April 4–1979 May 21 (Box 36, Folder 781)
    - Stubbing, Haydn, 1998 September 23 (Box 36, Folder 782)
    - Stubbing, Tony, 1976 February 14 (Box 36, Folder 783)
      Includes small painting
    - Sulfur, 1992 May 2–1999 November 27 (Box 36, Folder 784)
    - Sullivan, Ellen Wahl, 1984 September 27 (Box 36, Folder 785)
    - Sun & Moon Press, 1976-08-25-2002-02-12 (Box 36, Folder 786-787)
    - Sutro & Co., 1996 March 1 (Box 36, Folder 788)
    - Swanson, Elaine, 2006 March 4 (Box 36, Folder 789)
    - Swartz, Mark, 2002 February 6–2002 February 15 (Box 36, Folder 790)
    - Swayzee, Mary King, 1999 September 29–1999 October 22 (Box 36, Folder 791)
    - Swensen, Cole, 2005 November 18–2006 March 3 (Box 36, Folder 792)
    - Swetz van Middhlar, C. W., 1995 October 20 (Box 36, Folder 793)
    - Swiss Credit Bank, 1967 August 17 (Box 36, Folder 794)
    - Sylvester, David, 1962 June 21 (Box 36, Folder 795)
    - Sze, Arthur, 1988 January 18 (Box 36, Folder 796)
    - "S" General (Box 36, Folder 797)
    - Tabor, Don, 1988 February 19–2001 August 13 (Box 37, Folder 798)
      Includes two unidentified family photographs
    - Talisman, 1989 July 31–1989 October 3 (Box 37, Folder 799)
    - TALUS Magazine, 1986 August 5 (Box 37, Folder 800)
    - Tamminen, Suzanna, 2005 April 7 (Box 37, Folder 801)
    - Tao de Kitchen, 2005 February 21–2005 February 24 (Box 37, Folder 802)
    - Taproot Workshops, 1985 October 9 (Box 37, Folder 803)
    - Tarn, Nathanael, 1995 April 20 (Box 37, Folder 804)
    - Temple University, 1990 November 14 (Box 37, Folder 805)
    - Terrible Work, 1999 November 29 (Box 37, Folder 806)
    - 13th Moon, 1974 April 17–1974 November 3 (Box 37, Folder 807)
    - Thompson, Nikki, 2001 December 19–2002 February 13 (Box 37, Folder 808)
    - Tiber Press, 1954 May 4 (Box 37, Folder 809)
    - Tibor de Nagy Gallery, 1952 May 20–1996 May 23 (Box 37, Folder 810)
    - Tiddens, Kathy, 1983 February 2 (Box 37, Folder 811)
    - Tillery, Patrick C., 1997 September 2 (Box 37, Folder 812)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 1975 February 17 (Box 37, Folder 813)
    - Tinfish, 1995 November 6 (Box 37, Folder 814)
    - Torregian, Sotère, 1994 November 17 (Box 37, Folder 815)
    - Traggart, John, 1968 July 30–1991 July 27 (Box 37, Folder 816)
    - Treloar, Carol, 1979 May 25 (Box 37, Folder 817)
    - Tremblay-McGaw, Robin, 1987 January 14 (Box 37, Folder 818)
    - Tropp, Shawna, 1984 August 18–1984 October 16 (Box 37, Folder 819)
    - Truitt, Anne, 1965 May 4–1984 February 23 (Box 37, Folder 820)
    - Trumbull, Tom, 1969 July 4 (Box 37, Folder 821)
    - Tuttle, Richard, 2003 October 9 (Box 37, Folder 822)
    - Tysh, Chris, 1997 December 8 (Box 37, Folder 823)
    - Tyson, John, 2003 April 28–2003 April 29 (Box 37, Folder 824)
    - "T" General (Box 37, Folder 825)
    - University at Buffalo, 1991 October 30–2003 October 16 (Box 37, Folder 826)
    - University Club, 1990 April 26 (Box 37, Folder 827)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 2002 January 3 (Box 37, Folder 828)
    - University of California Press, 1995 November 6 (Box 37, Folder 829)
    - University of California, Riverside, 1975 October 20–1983 April 19 (Box 37, Folder 830)
    - University of California, San Diego, 1992 November 5 (Box 37, Folder 831)
    - University of California, Santa Cruz, 1997 April 15 (Box 37, Folder 832)
    - University of Connecticut, 1986 March 17 (Box 37, Folder 833)
    - University of Denver, 1990 September 21–1992 December 2 (Box 37, Folder 834)
    - University of Hawaii at Manoa, 1987 October 15–1987 November 30 (Box 37, Folder 835)
    - University of Iowa, 1963 May 20–1995 November 19 (Box 37, Folder 836)
    - University of Kansas, 1979 August 29 (Box 37, Folder 837)
    - University of Kentucky, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 838)
    - University of Nebraska, Lincoln, 1977 March 10 (Box 37, Folder 839)
    - University of Southern California, 1990 May 24–2005 April 2 (Box 37, Folder 840)
    - University of Tampa, 1965 May 10 (Box 37, Folder 841)
    - University of Texas, Austin, 1984 March 2–1984 June 8 (Box 38, Folder 842)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1980 May 14–1996 January 15 (Box 38, Folder 843)
    - University Press of New England, 1996 October 10–2003 March 6 (Box 38, Folder 844)
    - Unmuzzled Ox, 1975 February 1–1979 November 28 (Box 38, Folder 845)
    - Unterberg Poetry Center, 1999 July 15–1999 December 13 (Box 38, Folder 846)
    - Upshaw, Reagan, 1977 August 16–1978 February 2 (Box 38, Folder 847)
    - Upton, J. Duane, 1969 October 28 (Box 38, Folder 848)
    - "U" General (Box 38, Folder 849)
    - Van Dyke, Anne, 2003 January 22–2003 May 29 (Box 38, Folder 850)
    - Van Gogh's Ear, 2003 October 28–2005 September 14 (Box 38, Folder 851)
    - Verbena, Jeff, 1999 August 17 (Box 38, Folder 852)
    - Verse Press, 2005 April 1 (Box 38, Folder 853)
    - Vickery, Ann, 2002 April 19–2006 February 20 (Box 38, Folder 854)
    - Vicuña, Cecilia, 1998 January 11–2003 December 11 (Box 38, Folder 855)
    - Viking Penguin, 1987 May 7 (Box 38, Folder 856)
    - The Viking Press, 1972 June 26–1975 March 4 (Box 38, Folder 857)
    - The Village Voice, 1959 September 28 (Box 38, Folder 858)
    - Villigaluisson, Thor, 1974 March 18 (Box 38, Folder 859)
    - Violi, Paul, 1982 March 25–1982 April 15 (Box 38, Folder 860)
    - Vogelsang, Arthur, 1996 July 15–2005 March 15 (Box 38, Folder 861)
    - Voice Box, 1992 April 26 (Box 38, Folder 862)
    - VOLT, 1995 February 19–1996 December 16 (Box 38, Folder 863)
    - Voris, Laura, 2005 February 7–2005 August 19 (Box 38, Folder 864)
    - Vreeland, Sandra Isham, 1996 September 4 (Box 38, Folder 865)
    - "V" General (Box 38, Folder 866)
    - Wage, A. E., 1999 February 2 (Box 38, Folder 867)
    - Wagner, Cathy, 1996 October 21 (Box 38, Folder 868)
    - Waldman, Anne, 1967 March 9-2006 February 25 (Box 39, Folder 869)
    - Waldman, John, 1967 May 28 (Box 39, Folder 870)
    - Waldrop, Keith, 1983 October 25 (Box 39, Folder 871)
    - Waldrop, Rosmarie, 1975 June 24-2006 February 16 (Box 39, Folder 872-873)
    - Walker, Frank, 1984 June 18 (Box 39, Folder 874)
    - Walker, John, 1955 January 20–1984 May 9 (Box 39, Folder 875)
    - Walker, John H., 1956 May 24–1995 September 8 (Box 39, Folder 876)
    - Warren House Press, 1984 July 21 (Box 39, Folder 877)
    - Warsh, Lewis, 1983 May 21 (Box 39, Folder 878)
    - Watershed Foundation, 1984 May 17–1989 January (Box 39, Folder 879)
    - Watson, Steve, 1994 November 11–1995 May 30 (Box 39, Folder 880)
    - Wayne, Africa, 1999-10-12-2006-05-23 (Box 40, Folder 881-883)
    - Weber, Ben, 1957 May 24–1966 November 19 (Box 40, Folder 884)
    - Weigel, Frances, 2006 February 23 (Box 40, Folder 885)
    - Weiland, Andreas, 1973 February 15–1973 December 16 (Box 40, Folder 886)
    - Weir, Margaret, 2002 May 6 (Box 40, Folder 887)
    - Welish, Marjorie, 1985 September 27–2006 May 2 (Box 40, Folder 888)
    - Wesleyan University Press, 1996 April 11–2004 June 4 (Box 40, Folder 889-890)
    - Wesleyan University Press, 2004 May 20–2006 February 9 (Box 41, Folder 891)
    - Westward, 1940 April 16 (Box 41, Folder 892)
    - Wheeler, Susan, 1993 September 25–2005 June 30 (Box 41, Folder 893)
    - Whitehead, Molly, undated (Box 41, Folder 894)
    - White Walls, 1977 November 26 (Box 41, Folder 895)
    - Mrs. Giles Whiting Foundation, 1985 October 3 (Box 41, Folder 895a)
    - Wieners, John, 1957 May 23–1960 February 16 (Box 41, Folder 896)
    - Wild, Virginia, undated (Box 41, Folder 897)
    - Wilentz, Joan, 2003 April 19-2006 July 20 (Box 41, Folder 898)
    - Wilentz, Ted, 1967 August 1–1999 November 6 (Box 41, Folder 899)
    - Wilhelm, James J., 1987 February 11 (Box 41, Folder 900)
    - Wilkinson, Constance, 1974 July 31 (Box 41, Folder 901)
    - Wilkinson, Oliver, 1984 July 31–1988 February 15 (Box 41, Folder 902)
    - William Howard Studio, 1995 June 1 (Box 41, Folder 903)
    - Willis, Elizabeth, 2003 March 10 (Box 41, Folder 904)
    - Willis, Patricia C., 1986 January 16–1996 February 7 (Box 41, Folder 905)
    - Wilson, Geoffrey, 1991 September 19 (Box 41, Folder 906)
    - Wilson, Jane, 1952 October 13 (Box 41, Folder 907)
    - Wilson, Martha, 2005 February 8 (Box 41, Folder 908)
    - Winch, Terence, 1996 August 26 (Box 41, Folder 909)
    - Wissmann, Joan, 1986 May 10 (Box 41, Folder 910)
    - Witt-Diamant, Ruth, 1967 April 30 (Box 42, Folder 911)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1986 October 11 (Box 42, Folder 912)
    - Women in the Arts, 1976 March 26 (Box 42, Folder 913)
    - Woolmer, J. Howard, 1993 September 3 (Box 42, Folder 914)
    - Worthington, Marjorie, undated (Box 42, Folder 915)
    - Wright, Barbara, 1979 May 1 (Box 42, Folder 916)
    - Wright, C. D., 1991 February 23–2005 May 18 (Box 42, Folder 917)
    - Writers and Artists Protest, undated (Box 42, Folder 918)
    - Writers & Books, 1987 April 9 (Box 42, Folder 919)
    - Writers Harvest, undated (Box 42, Folder 920)
    - W. W. Norton & Company, 1996 January 21 (Box 42, Folder 921)
    - "W" General (Box 42, Folder 922)
    - Yaddo, 1957 January 23–1957 April 9 (Box 42, Folder 923)
    - Yale University Library, 1976 September 30–1995 August 2 (Box 42, Folder 924-925)
    - Yau, John, 1981 April 30 (Box 42, Folder 926)
    - Zawacki, Andrew, 2004 May 1–2006 July 20 (Box 42, Folder 927)
    - Zoland Books, 1992 August 12 (Box 42, Folder 928)
    - Z Press, 1973 September 8 (Box 42, Folder 929)
    - ZYZZYVA, 1995 January 3 (Box 42, Folder 930)
    - "XYZ" General (Box 42, Folder 931)
  - Other correspondence
    Other correspondence subseries contains family correspondence kept by Guest, including letters from her children, Hadley and Jonathan; drafts and unsent letters from Guest to various individuals; correspondence related to specific topics and correspondents grouped together by Guest; and postcards kept by Guest. Third party and unidentified correspondence are filed at the end of the subseries. Enclosures are noted when present.
    - Family correspondence
      - "Family correspondence" (Box 124, Folder 1794-1800)
        Correspondents are H. B[abrach], Higgings Trumbull, Easy Pelzel, John Pelzel, "Pinson", and S. Powel. Also among the correspondence are clippings on Alexander Calder and Charles H. Higgings, an unidentified note, menu for event, Hotel Rembrandt receipt, The Allen-Stevenson School brochure, and typed note from Higgins to Guest.
      - "Family correspondence and photographs", 1940–1967 (Box 125, Folder 1817-1821)
        Includes passports, clippings, academic records, Hadley Guest's cut hair, family photographs, negatives
      - Letters from children, 1960s (Box 125, Folder 1822)
        Jonathan and Hadley, 1960s; and from John and Louise Pelzel (uncle by marriage and aunt)
      - Guest-Pelzel Family Correspondence, 1948–1970 (Box 126, Folder 1830-1833)
        Includes printed material throughout
    - Letters from Barbara Guest to various individuals, 1989–1999 (Box 42, Folder 932-933)
    - Correspondence and postcards grouped together, 1973–1999 (Box 42, Folder 934-936)
    - Correspondence on specific topics
      - Wesleyan University Press regarding Durer in the Window: Reflections on American Art in the 1950s and 1960s by Barbara Guest, 2001 October 21–2002 February 22 (Box 43, Folder 937-938)
      - Correspondence with Tim Schaffner regarding the Schaffner Press Edition of Herself Defined, 2001 June 26–2002 February 12 (Box 43, Folder 939)
      - On Seeking Air, 1976–1978 (Box 43, Folder 940)
      - On various writings of Guest's (Box 43, Folder 941)
        Includes photograph of Guest
      - Regarding 2001 September 11 events (Box 44, Folder 942)
      - Correspondence with Sun and Moon Publisher Douglas Messerli regarding Guest's Fair Realism with drafts for book, 1987 October 23–1991 January 15 (Box 44, Folder 943)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 44, Folder 944-949)
    - Letter drafts and copies (Box 44, Folder 950-951)
      Includes unidentified photographs
    - "My writing: Doubleday, Verlag, etc. 1960s", 1961-1988 (Box 45, Folder 952-953)
      Correspondents are: Don Allen, Bill Berkson, Burning Deck, Joseph Cino, Pauline Cioffero, Dartmouth College, Mario Domandi, Doubleday, Maxine Groffsky, Carl Hanser, Institute of Contemporary Arts, Ironwood, Thomas H. Jackson, Thomas W. Leavitt, Louisiana State University, Gerard Melanga, Lynn McGee, Carl Morse, New York Times, The Paris Review, Alexander Pringle, Alison Samuel, Helga Sandburg, F.M. Shaine, Simon's Rock of Bard College, Jane Turner, Viking Penguin Inc., and The Washington Post
    - Folder of correspondence grouped together by Guest, 1962-1965 (Box 45, Folder 954-955)
      Correspondents are: Artists Theatre, Jason R. Berke, Sylvia E. Crane, Yvette Sakay Eastman, Hélène Eliat, Bob Fabian, Gloria Finn, Kerry Fischer, Anne Fremante,Getz, Mike Goldberg, Hadley Haden-Guest, Claire Higgins, Sheila Isham, Polly Kraft, Peter and Ann Law, Mary Mayer, Lynn Millar, Graves and Compton Morse, and Jean Paris.
    - Third party correspondence (Box 46, Folder 956-959)
    - Unidentified correspondence (Box 47, Folder 960-963)
    - Unidentified correspondence (Box 48, Folder 964-965)
      Includes photograph of Barbara Guest
    - Unidentified correspondence (Box 49, Folder 966-969)
    - Unsorted correspondence (Box 50, Folder 970-974)
- Writings, 1953-2004; Series II
  Organized into two subseries: Writings by Guest and Writings by others
  This series contains writings by Guest and writings of others. Writings by Guest includes drafts of her poetry, prose, drama, essays, lectures, lectures and reviews, and her biography on H.D. entitled Herself Defined: The Poet H.D. and Her World; and notes on kept by her throughout her writing process. Writings by others includes drafts by others that were sent to Guest for critique or are on Guest herself, reviews of Guest's published work, or are interviews with Guest.
  - Writings by Guest
    Organized into eight groupings: Poetry, Prose, Drama, Essays, Herself Defined: The Poet H. D. and Her World, Notes, Lectures by Guest, and Other writings.
    Poetry contains drafts of Guest's poems. Notable poetry publications represented include Bandusia, Blurred Edge, The Countess from Minneapolis, Defensive Rapture, Minatures and Other Poems, Poems, and Quilts. Drafts grouped together by Guest and unsorted poetry drafts and related papers are filed at the end of the subseries.
    Prose contains drafts of Guest's prose writings, including her novel, Seeking Air, and her prose poetry work, Rocks on a Platter: Notes on Literature.
    Drama contains Guest's dramatic writings, including "The Execution of Mary Stewart", "The Lady's Choice" and "The Office".
    Essays contains notebooks of essay drafts kept and titled by Guest, "Notebooks 1-8", and other essays, including essays on H.D. and other artists and writers.
    Herself Defined: The Poet H. D. and Her World contains correspondence, research notes, photographs, and working drafts of Guest's notable biography on H.D.
    Also in the subseries are various notes kept by Guest, lectures written and presented by Guest upon invitation, reviews by Guest on others' works, and drafts of Guest's bibliography.
    Material in this subseries includes handwritten, typescript, and composite drafts. Enclosures are noted when present.
    - Poetry
      - Abend Füllen, undated (Box 51, Folder 975)
        1 typescript, corrected
      - About Lost Paintings, undated (Box 51, Folder 976)
        1 typescript
      - The Addison Street Anthology, undated (Box 51, Folder 977)
        1 autograph manuscript
      - Ah Simple, undated (Box 51, Folder 978)
      - Alchemy of the Word, undated (Box 51, Folder 979)
      - All Elegies Are Black and White, undated (Box 51, Folder 980)
        1 autograph manuscript (on back of another typescript poem); 1 typescript, corrected
      - Altos; Surface as Object, undated (Box 51, Folder 981)
        Several typescripts, corrected
      - & In Memory of Braque, undated (Box 51, Folder 982)
      - Andreas' Song, undated (Box 51, Folder 983)
        1 typescript (note by hand)
      - Andromeda, undated (Box 51, Folder 984)
      - Another July, undated (Box 51, Folder 985)
        1 autograph manuscript; 2 typescripts
      - An Anthology of Scandinavian Literature, undated (Box 51, Folder 986)
      - The Artist, undated (Box 51, Folder 987)
        1 autograph manuscript; 1 typescript, corrected [not by Guest?]
      - Aspirancy, undated (Box 51, Folder 988)
      - Athletic Writing, undated (Box 51, Folder 989)
      - An Attachment, undated (Box 51, Folder 990)
      - Autobiograpy [sic], undated (Box 51, Folder 991)
        Several typescripts, corrected [name spelled "Autobiography" on one version, "Autobiograpy" on others]
      - Bandusia, undated (Box 51, Folder 992-993)
        3 typescripts and broadside
      - Barrels, undated (Box 51, Folder 994)
      - Beta in Greek, undated (Box 51, Folder 995)
        1 typescript, corrected [same poem as "Credo in Mortibus"]
      - Bicycling, undated (Box 51, Folder 996)
        2 typescripts, corrected
      - Birthday, undated (Box 51, Folder 997)
      - A Birthday Poem, 1964 March 23 (Box 51, Folder 998)
      - Black Chair, undated (Box 51, Folder 999)
        1 autograph manuscript; 1 typescript
      - The Blue Stairs, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 1000)
        Copy of poems from printed book
      - Blurred Edge, undated (Box 51, Folder 1001-1002)
        Many typescripts, corrected [collection, not single poem]
      - The Body Gate, undated (Box 51, Folder 1003)
        3 typescripts, corrected
      - Le Bon Bonbon Napoleon; Hawkes Chelmsford Rum & Butter; American Ginger, undated (Box 51, Folder 1004)
      - Bryher in the Breuer Chair, undated (Box 51, Folder 1005)
      - Calends, undated (Box 51, Folder 1006)
        2 typescripts
      - Carmen, 1963 January (Box 51, Folder 1007)
        1 autograph manuscript, 1 typescript
      - Central Park, 1967 February (Box 51, Folder 1008)
      - Chalk, undated (Box 51, Folder 1009)